Welcome [music] to the Expense Agent
setup video.
Today, I will show you how to configure
the Expense Agent in Business Central.
I'm at the role center right now, and
you can see the avatar shows up with
Expense Agent, just like other agents in
Business Central.
I can go ahead and hover over the avatar
and activate it.
It opens a configuration wizard, where
it gives
me options to configure how the Expense
Agent will behave, and also configuring
the default setup for the expense module
itself.
To begin with, we have access and
submission,
where we can control how the expenses
can be submitted by the external expense
users.
We have a web app link, and then we have
also an option to send emails with the
receipt.
I can configure the account right here,
where I choose the M365 email account.
It's It's usually a shared mailbox,
and then I can define who can access
the Expense Agent via the web app or the
email account.
If I go to submit expenses, here I can
see nine users are already registered,
and I have the option to add all my
employees or existing employees to the
expense user list, or I can also import
expense user from M365 graph.
I have already configured myself as an
expense user, so I'll go back, and I can
see nine registered users. Then, we have
option to configure default approver.
This is the person who can approve
everyone's expenses.
We have added this option to make it
easier for the Expense Agent admin to
add one approver, but they can do more
granular
approver setup in a different page.
Going to the next page in the wizard, we
have some accounting defaults. Here, as
an admin, I can choose whether I need to
insert the number series. I can also
preview them even before inserting them.
It also shows in status where if my
number series already exists, so I I
don't have to insert them or even if I
insert them, nothing will happen. It
will just skip them.
For example, in the payment methods,
I can see it is recommending bank as a
payment method with reimbursement type
company paid.
If I like it, I can choose to keep it.
Similarly, for posting group,
we have
default posting group suggestions.
And for categories, we have something
similar
where I can see if there are any new
categories which are being suggested.
And I can decide to either keep it or
not keep it. And even if I keep it, it
will just skip over the records.
Moving on, we have management defaults
which are defining some expense
locations and management rules.
And all of them have preview built in
where you can see what data or what
records will be inserted in the system.
And system is smart enough to auto
select these when it detects there are
no data in the system. If there is
nothing in the system, it will auto
enable the defaults, but you can of
course disable it.
Going to the next page, we get into
rules and controls. This is where I can
select whether I want to enforce the
management rules whichever we just
created.
And there are additional properties like
whether I want to display an
anti-corruption attestation.
Or do I want the expense user to always
add a receipt number in when they submit
an expense or a merchant name?
For communication, we can specify an
email account which will be used to send
notification to the end user. I can see
it is blank right now.
But this means I need to just go back
and set up my email account. And once
I've configured it, it should
auto-populate the outbox email as well
to the default one.
Now I see the send email has been set to
an email which I want. I can also change
it to an outbox or no-reply email
account and then I can decide how do I
want to notify the end user. There are
different options for notifications.
And do I also want to notify for
approval updates? I can also control
that.
On the next page, we have mileage
expenses. Here we can configure how the
mileage expenses are calculated based on
rate per unit and the unit of measure
right now.
We have also added project tracking
where
you can allow expense user to track an
expense against a specific project.
In the visibility, you can control
whether you want to show the expense
user all the projects or just the
assigned projects which they are
associated with.
Finally, we have per diem expenses where
you can define the per diem calculation
rules. There are different options.
Of course, you can then go into finer
details about specifying different rules
and how the reductions are applied.
Once you're satisfied with the setup,
what you can do is you can just go to
activate and update the setup.
Once the agent has been activated, you
can go to the expense users list. You
can select all the users who you want to
send a welcome email.
This welcome email consists of all the
details they need to use the expense web
app portal or where to send the expense
receipts in an email to.
That's how you configure expense agent.
Thank you for watching.